本庭在此判你服刑 斯科菲尔德先生
I find it incumbent that you see the inside of a prison cell.
你为什么这么急着要见布伦斯?
Why do you want to see Burrows
因为他是我哥哥
Because he's my brother.
所以你就来这里陪他?
So you get yourself tossed into Fox River with him?
为了什么... 救他么?
To what? Save him?
不管陷害我的是谁
And whoever it was that set me up wants me
都是想尽快将我除掉
in the ground as quickly as possible.
听着 日子越接近
Look,the closer it gets,
我就越担心事情会被抖出来
the more I'm worried that the bottom will fall out of this whole thing.
这就是那个指控阿布鲁奇的混蛋
That son of a bitch fingered Abruzzi.
有人发现了菲波纳奇
Someone found Fibonacci.
是谁
Who was this someone?
为什么要雇他
Why'd you hire him?
靠近你的朋友 更加靠近你的敌人
Keep your friends close,and your enemies closer.
约翰 你动我试试看
Hey, come at me, John
我你孙子跪地求饶
I'm coming after you.
我不信
I doubt it.
我要把你弄出去
I'm getting you out of here.
不可能
It's impossible.
除非这地方是你自己设计的
Not if you designed the place it isn't.
你看过蓝图了
You've seen the blueprints.
远不止如此
Better than that.
我已经纹在身上了
I've got 'em on me.
你的眼光总是放的很远
You're anticipating every one of my moves three moves in advance.
简直是个战略家
You're a hell of a strategist, fish.
想过回波士顿么
You ever think about Boston?
当然
Sure.
想再去看看么
Think you'll ever see it again?
我已经60岁的老头了 还有60年的刑期
I'm a 60-year-old man with 60 years left on my ticket.
你是怎么想的?
What do you think?
我就打算走出去
I'm thinking about going.
偷偷摸摸的还是大摇大摆的
Well, there's going and there's going.
你指哪个呢
Which one do you mean?
你心里面认为的哪个
The one you think I mean.
怎么有你这样的 刚进来三天就想开溜了
Three days inside and he's already thinking about turning rabbit.
你会习惯的
It'll pass.
刚来的都这样
It always does.
现在有更重要的事值得关注
Got bigger things to worry about at the moment.
经验告诉我将有大事发生
I've been in here long enough to know it when I see it.
暴风雨前的宁静
The calm before the storm.
黑人和白人即将开战了
Whites and blacks are going at each other real soon here.
人人选择自己的归属 然后便是血流成河
Everybody chooses sides and a lot of guys bleed.
为什么呢
There a reason?
就像不能把猫和狗关在一起
Same reason you don't put cats and dogs in the same cage.
他们是天生的死对头
They don't get along.
嗯
Hm.
怎么了
What?
马桶冲不了水了
Toilet won't flush.
那么
So?
只有一种可能
Means only one thing, fish.
这样你就无法冲走违禁品
You can't flush your contraband.
我们没什么可担心的
We got nothing to worry about.
那只是你
Says who?
桌子下面
Under the table
这是什么玩意儿
What the hell is this?
防身用的 赶快把它藏起来
It's insurance, white boy. Now dump it.
把门打开
Open it.
这样看来
So,
用来充当种族骚动的武器么
tooling up for the race riot, are we?
把它交给我
Hand it over.
黑白之战
Huh. Rughead and the Billy.
那么你站在哪一边呢 小嫩鸡
Which side are you on, anyhow, fish?
都不是 长官
That would be neither, boss.
或许你会在户外活动时带上它
Maybe you're gonna go extracurricular with it, then.
用它来伤害狱警也说不定
Stick a CO, maybe.
有什么问题么 副警长
Is there a problem here, deputy?
找到一把匕首
Got a shank in here.
是你的么
Is this yours?
看你也不像是说谎的
You're not a good liar.
苏克雷 去禁闭室
Come on, Sucre. You're going to the SHU.
去别的地方看看 副警长
Move along.Deputy
这间牢房的事情还没处理完呢
I'm not done shaking this cell down yet.
我说让你去别的地方看看
I said move along.
有老头子为你撑腰啊
In the old man's back pocket, are you?
我告诉你 小嫩鸡
Well, I got news for you, fish.
白天这里也许他说了算
He may run this place during the day,
但是晚上却由我管
but I run it during the night.
迈克尔 和我说说你的计划
What the hell were you thinking, Michael?
我们怎么出去?
How are we doing it?
医务室
The infirmary.
Infirmary.
那里是保安系统的最薄弱环节
It's the weakest link in the security chain.
一旦我拿到 方纳克
If I get that PUGNAC,
我就能得到所有的一切
I'll get all the access I need.
方纳克 是什么东西
What the hell's a PUGNAC?
降低我的胰岛素指标 看上去就像得了糖尿病
It lowers my insulin levels to the point that I'm hyperglycemic.
只要医生认为我患有糖尿病
As long as the good doctor thinks I'm diabetic,
我就有时间在那里做一切我想做的
I'll have time there to do what I need to do.
那是什么
Which is?
一些琐碎的工作
A little work.
一些准备工作
A little prep for your arrival.
无论如何 这就是我的办法
That's the idea, anyway.
办法
The idea?
拿到 方纳克 需要费点力气 仅此而已
There's a little hitch in getting the PUGNAC.
他们是不会在药房里卖这个药的
They don't exactly stock it at the commissary.
费了半天劲就为了拿那几片药
This thing's riding on a bunch of pills?
咱俩谈话的时候已经有人在想办法了
Someone's working on it as we speak.
这时候相信一个黑人狱友 可不是什么明智之举 迈克尔
Now's not the time to trust a black inmate.
我们的关系和种族无关
Our relationship transcends race.
在这里没有什么能够超越种族歧视
Nothing transcends race in here.
我不能让你这么做
I can't let you do it.
好好表现 三年后你就会离开这里了
Good behaviour,you're outta here in three years.
应该比那个早的多
Gonna be a whole lot sooner then that.
根本行不通
It can't be done.
根本行不通 迈克尔
Can't be done, Michael.
没有人能从 狐狸河监狱 逃出去
No one's ever broken out of Fox River.
一切都在掌握之中
Every step's already been mapped out.
包括所有的可能性
Every contingency.
所有的可能
Every contingency?
虽然你有这地方的蓝图
You may have the blueprints of this place,
但有一样东西你是无法控制的 那就是人
but there's one thing those plans can't show you...people,
阿布鲁奇 那样的人
Guys like Abruzzi.
你显然是看错他们了 他们迟早会对付你的
You so much as look at these guys the wrong way, they'll cut you up.
对这些人而言
As far as these guys are concerned,
我只不过是另一名虚度光阴囚犯
I'm just a con doing his time,
不会有什么问题的
staying out of trouble.
在这里不是你找麻烦 而是麻烦主动找你
You don't gotta look for trouble. It finds you.
他们找上门来时 我们早已远走高飞了
And when it does, we'll be long gone.
你简直疯了
This is madness.
你连牢房都出不去
You can't get outta your cell.
并非如此
Not true.
什么 你有钥匙
What, you got a key?
差不多吧
Something like that.
坐错地方了 小嫩鸡
For the brothers at my side,Fish
这里是帝博格的地盘
Belongs to T-Bag.
谁
Who?
你说话最好放尊重点 小嫩鸡
You best speak with respect, Fish.
这家伙在巴马时绑架了不少孩子
Man kidnapped half a dozen boys and girls down in 'Bama,
先奸后杀
raped 'em and killed 'em.
先杀后奸也说不定
Wasn't always in that order, either.
帝博格 有真实的姓名么
Does T-Bag have a real name?
那就是我真正的名字
That is my real name.
没事 没事 没事 请上坐
No, no, no. Please... sit.
你就是传说中的那个新人
So you're the new one I been hearin' all the rave reviews about.
斯科菲尔德
Scofield.
你就和传说中的一样漂亮啊
One thing's for sure, you're just as pretty as advertised.
甚至 更可爱
Prettier, even.
黑鬼吓着你了 不是么
Rugheads got you scared, do they?
你说啥?
Sorry?
所以你才坐到这里
Assume that's why you're over here.
进来的人都知道
Few days on the inside,
虔诚的白人终于认清了现实
any God-fearing white man realizes the correctional system's
在处理黑人和白人问题上 产生了严重的偏移
got a serious lean toward the African-American persuasion.
我倒没发现
I hadn't noticed
他们以为人多势众 就胜券在握了
They got the numbers all right, so they think they do as they please.
有一个东西是他们所没有的
We got one thing they don't..
那就是 突袭
surprise.
我们很快就要大干一场了
We gonna take the ball game to them real soon.
你第一次经历可能会比较难受
It's gonna be nasty for a first-timer like you
不过我们会保护你的 我会保护你的
We'll protect you. I'll protect you.
你要做的只是
All you gotta do is...
抓住这只口袋
take this pocket right here
这样生活将变得很美好
and your life'll be all peaches and cream.
我走的时候你就跟着我
I walk, you walk with me.
就没人敢伤害你
I'll keep you real close so no one up in here can hurt you.
可你已经有女朋友了
Looks to me you already got a girlfriend.
这里还有一个呢
I got a whole 'nother pocket over here.
我会没事的
I'll pass.
如果我不保护你
I don't protect you,
黑人们会像对待一盘豆子一样把你吃掉
them rugheads gonna gobble you up like a plate of black-eyed peas.
我说 不
I said no.
那你现在就最好滚开
Then you'd best move, then.
马上滚
Now.
你有种再来我的地盘
You come around these bleachers again,
就再也不是只动嘴说说了
it's gonna be more than just words we're exchanging.
懂我的意思么
Know what I'm saying?
不好意思
Excuse me.
请问您是林肯·布伦斯的辩护律师 提姆·伊莱斯吗
Are you the Tim Giles that represented Lincoln Burrows?
好吧 如果你是记者的话
Okay, if you're a reporter...
我不是记者 我和被告认识
I'm not a reporter. I know the defendant.
你们是亲戚
Oh. You family?
也算不上
Not exactly.
几年前我们曾交往过
We were in a relationship a few years back.
你看 女士 我
Well, look, ma'am, I, uh...
我不知道怎么告诉你 那个人的确有罪
I..I don't know what to tell you. I mean, the man was guilty.
已经盖棺定论了
The prosecution's case was a slam dunk.
就因为受害人是副总统的兄弟
Because the victim was the Vice President's brother.
如果你指的是联邦政府介入的话
If you're suggesting that the federal government rammed this thing through,
我也不想这样 毕竟我是他的辩护律师
okay,I take offense to that, 'cause I fought for that guy.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
证据就在那儿
The evidence was there.
林肯 为斯蒂德曼的公司工作
Lincoln worked for Steadman's company.
他当众和这个人发生争执 于是就被解雇了
He gets into a public altercation with the guy, so, he gets fired.
两周后 斯蒂德曼被枪杀了
Two weeks later, Steadman's shot dead.
凶器在林肯家被找到
The murder weapon is found in Lincoln's house,
而且他衣服上还有受害人的血迹
and the victim's blood found on his clothes
相信我 的确有很多案件使你夜不能眠
Trust me, there are cases you lose sleep over, but
但决不是这件
this isn't one of 'em
那么 克拉勃·西蒙思 呢
What about Crab Simmons?
林肯 说他能为他作证
Lincoln said he could exonerate him.
为什么你不让他出庭呢
Why didn't you put him on the stand?
那哥们已经 五进宫了
The man's a five-time felon, all right?
他 他毫无信誉可言
He-He... He had no credibility.
你不介意我去拜访一下他吧
So you wouldn't mind if I paid him a visit?
你随便 但我觉得这对你一点好处都没有
Be my guest.But I don't think it'll do you any good.
感觉很奇怪 我也说不清是怎么回事
Strange feeling. Don't know how to explain it.
现在
Now, um...
我的生活一直充斥着疯狂
usually, my whole life, it's always been crazy,
喧嚣
noisy,
甚至发狂 但是
maddening, you know, in my head, but...
现在却很平静
right now, it's quiet.
很完美
It's perfect.
你回来我很高兴
I'm glad you came back.
我时时刻刻都惦记着你
I thought about you the whole time.
你也知道 我这一生犯了不少错误
You know, I made a lot of mistakes in my life.
我也知道错了
I know that.
我想改正
I'm gonna make it right.
我知道你会的
I know you will.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
我想要留住这一刻
I want to remember this.
不要
No.
别这样 来吧 拜托 就一张
Oh, come on. Come on, Vi, please. Just one.
好吧
OK.
别紧张 伙计
Easy, man.
方纳克 搞定了吗
How are we doing on the PUGNAC?
嘿 我正在想办法呢
Hey, I'm working on it.
你得抓紧 我今晚就需要那个东西
Well, work faster. I need that stuff tonight.
医务室有什么东西这么吸引你
What's up there in that infirmary that you need so bad?
帮我搞到 方纳克 或许我会告诉你
You get me that PUGNAC and maybe I'll tell you.
我认为咱们说的已经够明白的了
Thought we had an understanding.
这里只提供给家庭成员
This here's for the family.
你已经表明不是家庭成员了
You made it pretty clear you ain't blood.
把那东西拿过来怎样
How about you hand that over?
不错的钢条 只需稍做加工
Nice looking piece of steel,bit of work.
就能成为很好的武器
You could do some serious damage with it.
可问题是 你究竟想伤害谁呢
Question is, who was it you was plannin' on damaging?
我曾看到你和黑鬼在一起
I seen you with the Negroes, you know.
或许你已经成为他们中的一员了
Well, maybe you're one of them milk chickens,
还一脸茫然
all confused, like.
外表是白人 骨子里却像石油一样黑
White on the outside,black as tar on the inside.
真想到你体内看一下 你说是吧
Maybe we oughta take a look at them insides and find out.
女童子军们
Girl Scouts,
你们那里有什么问题么
is there a problem over there?
咱们今天就算了 如果你觉得没问题的话
I think we'll just hang onto this if that's OK with you.
我的话只说一遍 赶快解散 娘娘腔们
Hey! I'm not gonna ask you again.Let's break up the party, ladies.
你也听到他的话了吧 小可怜
You heard the man, little doggie.
走吧
Get along.
怎么才能制服一个狱友
What's it take to shake down another inmate?
让他归还本来属于你的东西
Get something he's taken from you?
我要 菲波纳奇 作为交换
It would take Fibonacci.
我会给你 菲波纳奇 的
Well, I'll give you Fibonacci.
我答应过你
I promise you that.
等时机成熟了
When the time is right.
时机已经很成熟了
The time is right now.
当咱俩都站在高墙之外时才可以
No, when you and I are both standing outside those walls.
不用过着假释的生活
You're on life without parole.
跨越高墙是多么遥不可及的阿
You'll never stand outside those walls.
除非你认识什么人
Not unless you knew someone,
而这个人知道如何离开这里
someone who knew a way out.
你认为如何 约翰
What do you say, John?
你简直是年度最佳鬼扯编剧
I say I've heard nothing but blabber.
菲利·法佐尼
Philly Falzone.
真是荣幸
It's an honour.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我 嗯...
Well, I, um...
我一直认为我们亲如兄弟
I just thought we'd, you know, fraternize
他还真像 不是么
He looks like it, doesn't he?
像什么
Looks what?
就像大家说的一样
Like everybody's been saying.
你没有睾丸
You got no sack.
你被阉了
You've been neutered.
你不应该这么和我说话
You shouldn't talk to me like that.
你过去是给我洗衣服的
You used to pick up my laundry.
时过境迁了 约翰
Not any more.
约翰 传闻这里有人知道 菲波纳奇 的下落
John,word is that someone in here knows where Fibonacci is,
可是你却无动于衷
and you're not doing anything about it.
我正在办呢
I'm working on it.
我想你的速度还不够快
Well, you're not working on it fast enough.
很显然 菲波纳奇 很快就要露面了
Apparently, Fibonacci's coming up for air again.
下月有个听证会
Next month, a Congressional hearing.
如果他去作证的话
Now, if he testifies at that hearing,
会有很多人要倒台的
a lot of people are going down,
包括我
including me.
咱们也认识好久了
Now, I've known you a long time.
咱们的妻子又都是好朋友
Our wives are friends,
咱们的孩子又在同一所天主教学校读书
our kids go to the same Catholic school
你孩子要是出了意外 我会感到很惭愧的
Now, it would be a shame if anything were to happen to your kids.
我的孩子会想他们的
I know my kids would miss them.
你没必要这么做
You don't need to do this.
我有
I do.
我会找到这个人的
I'll get this guy.
然后搞定 菲波纳奇
We'll get Fibonacci.
好 为了大家 希望你是对的
Well, for everyone's sake, I hope you're right.
没错
I am.
保重 约翰
Be well, John.
多谢
Thank you.
长官 我要打电话
Yo, badge, I gotta use the phone.
是的 没问题 还是比萨和足疗么
Sure. You want a pizza and a pedicure too?
不 今天是周一 天啊
No. It's-It's Monday, man.
我要给女朋友打电话 她在等我的电话呢
I gotta call my girl. She's expecting my call.
闭上你的臭嘴吧 你什么都别想了
Put a sock in it. You got nothin' comin'.
不 不 不
No, no, no, man! No, man!
查一下名单
Hey, pull up the manifest.
在数据库里有个叫 艾伦·施瓦茨 的人么
Is there an Allen Schweitzer in gen pop?
没有
No.
隔离室里呢
How about the SHU?
没有
No.
为什么问这个
Why you asking?
好奇而已
Curious, that's all.
听到号角声了么 小嫩鸡
You hear the trumpets, Fish?
我知道你听到了
I know you hear'em.
末日审判
That's Judgment Day
就快来了 很快
It's comin'... real soon
你在我这里干什么
What are you doing in my cell?
我要加入
I want in.
我没听清楚 小嫩鸡
I'm not quite sure I heard that, Fish.
你说你要加入
Did you just say you're in?
没错
That's right.
有句老话说的好
You know the old saying, don't you?
得寸进尺
In for an inch, in for a mile.
无论有什么后果
Whatever it takes.
你让我打 我就打
You want me to fight, I'll fight.
看台的那个螺钉 就是用来做这个的
The bolt from the bleachers-- that's what it was for
你想要打架 会有机会的
Well, you wanna fight,you're gonna get your chance.
下一次点名
Next count.
-今晚 -有什么问题么
-Tonight? -Problem with that?
因为我们要从正面打垮他们
'Cause we goin' straight at 'em.
你最好先有个准备 小嫩鸡
Better catch a square, Fish.
我们人手极缺
We undermanned in a big way.
我需要武器
All I need's a weapon.
你想要武器么 狗娘养的
You want a weapon, bitch?
给你
There you go.
犯人都回到自己牢房
All prisoners return to cells.
在干大事之前你必须向我们证实你的忠诚
You have to prove yourself before we trust you with the heavy artillery.
懂我的话么
Know what I'm sayin'?
关上门
Gates closing
我为上次的匆忙对话向您道歉
I wanted to apologize for being so short with you before.
没事
No problem.
越是接近死刑执行日
Closer it gets to an execution,
形势就越发的紧张 我想把这个交给你
the harder it becomes, so that's why I wanted to give you this.
这是事发当晚车库的监控录像
It's the, uh, surveillance tape of the garage that night.
封闭的庭审 所以法庭以外的人都看不到
It was a closed trial, so no one outside of the courtroom saw it.
希望能对你有所帮助
I thought it could help you out.
-帮助我什么 -放弃
-With what? -Closure.
艾伦·施瓦茨
Allen Schweitzer.
这个名字和你有关么
That name mean anything to you?
应该有吗
Should it?
我不知道 所以才来问你
I don't know. You tell me.
从没听说过
Never heard of the guy.
你确定
Are you sure?
我确定
Positive.
你还好么 小白脸
Ah, what's up, snowflake?
你以为我傻
Do you think I'm a fool?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我看到你和 希特勒·犹思 在一起
I see you up there with the Hitler Youth.
我现在就想把你大卸八块
I got a good mind to slash you open right now.
并不像你想象中的那样
It's not what you think.
他们有我想要的东西
They've got something I need.
真好笑
Now, see, that's funny,
因为我也有你想要的
because I got something you need too.
你不是想要 方纳克么
You want your PUGNAC, fish? Huh?
都在这里 亲爱的 都是你的了
I hate 'em, baby. So will you.
你的好运到此为止了
Listen, white boy. Your luckjust ran out.
你选错阵营了
You chose the wrong side.
看到你真高兴
Man, it's great to see your face.
别再玩了 好不
I think it's time you quit the charade,don't you?
什么
What?
别人的生活都被你破坏了
It's starting to ruin people's lives.
迈克尔也进来了 只因为他认为你是无辜的
Michael's in here 'cos he thinks you're innocent.
他告诉你的
What's he told you?
他什么都没告诉我 但是我知道 林肯
He hasn't told me anything, but I know.
我知道他是怎么想的
I know what he's planning.
叫他停手吧
Call him off.
你要是爱他的话 就叫他停手吧
If you love him, call him off.
我看过录像带了
I saw the tape.
那是伪造的
That's not how it went down.
我知道我看见的是什么
I know what I saw.
我只知道我看到的
我当时在场 还记得么
I was there, remember?
那晚我喝多了
I got high that night.
我是被逼的
I had to.
我别无选择
It was the only way I could go through with it.
我根本没开枪
I never pulled the trigger.
那人早已经死了
The guy was already dead.
是的 当然 你和我说过不下千遍了
Yeah, I know. You've told me a thousand...
听着 我是被陷害的
Then listen! I was set up!
我那晚去那只是想让他还钱
I went there that night to clear a debt.
克拉勃·西蒙思 要我还他的9万美元
Crab Simmons was on my ass for the 90 grand I owed him.
他告诉我目标是个毒犯
He told me the mark was some scumbag drug dealer
事成之后 我们就两清了
and if I took it we'd be clean.
我根本就没扣扳机
I never pulled the trigger
我所知道的就是有人想让我去 特伦斯.斯蒂德曼 所在的车库
All I know is that somebody wanted me in the same garage as Terrence Steadman that night.
他们为什么要陷害你
Why would somebody want to set you up?
不是我 是他
It wasn't about me. It was about him.
斯蒂德曼
Steadman?
是的
Yes.
他就像个圣人
The guy was like a saint
从事慈善事业
All the charity work,
还有他公司在做的环保改革
the environmental progress his company was making...
这里只有你一人有杀害他的动机
About the only person in this entire country who had motive to kill him was you.
你来这就是想说我有罪么
You came all the way down here to tell me how guilty I am?
我也不知道自己来的目的
I don't know why I came here.
你现在有了自己的生活
You have your life now. I know that.
我知道
I know that...
如果你念旧情的话
but if what we had before meant anything to you,
希望你能找到真相
you'd find out the truth.
或许这就是事实呢
Maybe all this is the truth.
又或许他们是对的呢
Maybe they got it right.
长官
Badge!
开门啊 长官
Open up, Badge!
又怎么了
You talking again?
今天是我女朋友的生日
It's my girl's birthday.
那祝她生日快乐好了
Happy birthday to her, then.
让我给她打个电话吧 求你了
You gotta let me call her! Please!
如果你让我给她打电话的话 我给你一百万
I'll give you a million dollars, if you let me use the phone.
我看过你的帐户 苏克雷
I seen your kicks, Sucre.
你名下好像只有40美分
You got something like 40 cents to your name.
求你了
Please!
天啊 不要
God, no!
你好啊 玛丽克鲁兹 还在等什么 快来吧
All right. Maricruz. What are you doing? Come on.
没关系 赫克特 你去吧
Yeah, it's okay, Hector. You go ahead.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我想我还是找辆出租吧
I think I'm just going to take a cab.
你说什么 回家 不是刚到么
What do you mean, like, go home? I mean, you just got here.
他没给你打电话 是不
He didn't call you, did he?
我也非常喜欢 费尔南多 但这家伙游手好闲
Look... I love Fernando to death, but the guy's a deadbeat.
你的生活还要继续
You got to move on with your life.
伊莱斯 先生
Mr. Giles,
如果可以 还能否找您谈谈
we'd like to have a word with you, if we could.
我真的很忙
I really don't have time.
不好意思 情况紧急
I'm afraid we're going to have to insist.
我们注意到是您提出了信息公开申请
It's come to our attention that you made a FOIL request
就在几天前 关于布伦斯的案子
a couple of days ago, on the Burrows case.
是的 那么
Yeah. So?
记录显示你您把监控录像做了拷贝
Records show that you made a dupe of the surveillance tape.
没错
That's right.
能知道为什么吗
Mind us asking why?
是为了他的一个前任女友
It's for one of Burrows' old girlfriends, man.
她一直坚信那个人是无辜的
She was under the impression that the guy was innocent.
于是我就想让她早点放弃算了
I figured it'd, you know, help her with closure
那么现在录像带在她那里
She's in possession of the tape now, then?
别跟我这样
Don't pull that card on me.
信息公开自由
It's the Freedom of Information Act.
她有权拥有那盘录像带
She's entitled to that tape as much as you or I are.
是的 是的 没错
Oh,no, no, by all means, by all means.
-我可以走了么 -还有一件事
-May I go now? -Just one more thing.
他这个前女友
This old girlfriend of his...
叫什么名字
what's her name?
不好意思
Excuse me.
西蒙思 是住这儿么
Is this the Simmons residence?
我是 西蒙思 太太
I'm Ms. Simmons.
对不起 我
I'm sorry. Um,
我是 维罗妮卡·多诺万
I'm Veronica Donovan.
我想找一下 克拉勃·西蒙思 你们是亲戚么
I'm looking for Crab Simmons. Are you related?
他是我儿子
He's my son.
他在家么
Is he around?
不在
No.
能告诉我在哪能找到他么
Could you tell me where I could find him?
女士 你走吧 我帮不了你 难道你还不明白么
Lady, go away. I can't help you. Can't you understand that?
实在抱歉 我只是
Look, I'm sorry.It's just...
有人危在旦夕 或许您的儿子能帮上忙
a man's life is at stake,and maybe your son can help him.
克拉勃已经帮不上谁的忙了 女士
Crab can't help nobody, lady.
他已经死了
He's dead
对不起
I'm sorry.
注意 都站到门口
Heads up! 7-up, cons, stand your gate!
好戏就要上演了 小嫩鸡
'Bout to jump off, Fish.
鲍尔 回到你的位置
Ballard, get back on your number.
请求支援
I need backup
我说了回到原位
I said back on your number!
救我
Help me...
斯科菲尔德
Scofield!
你死定了 斯科菲尔德
You're a dead man, Scofield!
你听见了么
You hear me?!
你死定了
You're a dead man!
我不知道该说你们什么了
I really don't know what to say to you gentlemen.
我试着不去怀疑你们
I try to give you the benefit of the doubt,
试着去尊重你们
I try to treat you with respect.
但你们自己却不尊重自己
You can't even respect yourselves.
今后的48小时 将是一级防范禁闭期
So, there's going to be a 48-hour lockdown.
不许吃饭 不许洗澡
No mess. No showers.
不许探监
No visitation.
我强烈建议你们学会相处
And I strongly suggest that you all learn to get along.
否则的话 下次将会是一周
Otherwise, the next time, it's going to be a week,
再往后 就有可能是一个月
and the time after that, it's going to be a month.
好好想想吧
Think about it.
有位叫 莱提莎·巴里斯 的人找你
Got a Leticia Barres on the line.
我不认识他 先让她留言吧
I don't know who that is. Take a message.
她说她曾和 克拉勃·西蒙思 约会过
She says she used to date Crab Simmons.
莱提莎 很感谢你能来电
Leticia, thank you for calling.
要是想和我谈话
You want to hear what I have to say,
我们必须在公共场合会面 这样他们就抓不到我们了
we meet in a public place, where they can't get to us.
等等 等等 等等 谁要抓咱们
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Where who can't get to us?
你到底要不要听我说
You want to hear what I have to say or not?
要是不想听的话 我马上就挂
'Cause if you don't, I'm going to hang up right now.
不 不 不 请告诉我时间和地点
No, no, no... you just name the time and the place.
这里
Over here
莱提莎 非常感谢你能来
Leticia, thanks for coming..
省省吧 女士
Go easy, lady
我们素不相识 明白吗
We don't know each other, you got that?
在这里他们就没法抓到我们了
We'll stay out here in the open where they can't get to us.
在这他们不能做他们想做的
Where they can't do what they do.
我想和你谈话的唯一理由
Only reason why I'm talking to you
就是因为他们会像杀我的丈夫那样来 对付你的男友
'cause they gonna kill your boy like they killed mine.
验尸报告说是海洛因害死了你丈夫 莱提莎
Coroner's report says smack killed your boyfriend, Leticia.
是吸食过量所致 不是吸食过量
It was an overdose. Wasn't no overdose
你什么意思
What do you mean?
克拉勃从不吸毒 他有心脏病
Crab didn't use. He had a bad heart.
要是沾上毒品的话 会使他毙命
If he touched the stuff, it'd kill him.
你不觉得事情太巧合了么
I mean, don't you think it's just the slightest bit of a coincidence
在你男朋友出事后一周他就死了
he OD'd a week after your boyfriend's crime?
他们是要杀他灭口
They killed him 'cause he knew things.
他们不想让事情泄漏出去
Things they didn't want to get out.
比如
Like what?
比如谁是那晚的真凶
Like who was really behind that hit that night.
肯定不是 克拉勃
Wasn't Crab, that's for damn sure
也肯定不是 林肯
And it sure as hell wasn't Lincoln
他们俩根本就不知道是怎么被卷进去的
Neither of them boys knew what they were getting into.
他们都被别人利用了
They were just pawns in a big game
你说什么
What?
-他们来了 -谁来了 莱提莎
-They're here. -Who's here, Leticia?
别跟着我
Don't try to follow me.
也不要找我 我是不会作证的
Don't find me. I won't testify.
能不能再和我说说
Just slow down and talk to me.
你我还是走的越远越好
I'd get as far away from here as you can, girl.
因为没有他们抓不到的人
'Cause there ain't nobody they can't get to.
莱提莎
Leticia!
您好
Hello?
遇到点小麻烦
We have a small complication.
有个律师牵扯进来了
There's a lawyer poking around.
维罗妮卡·多诺万
Veronica Donovan.
是的
Yes.
你应该能搞定一个
You can handle a girl who graduated
从贝纳法学院毕业的女孩
in the middle of her Baylor law school class.
至少我是这么认为的
At least I'd like to think so,
不能拿咱们正在做的事情冒险
given the stakes of what we're dealing with here.
任何危害到咱们的人都要消灭
Anyone that's a threat to what we're doing is expendable.
任何人
Anyone.
明白
Understood.
那就尽你所能把事情做好吧
Then do what you need to do to make this go away.
你在么 亲爱的
You there, Pretty?
我知道你在
I know you're there.
我会来找你的
Just want you to know I'm coming for you.
你哪儿也跑不了
You got nowhere to run.
你被困在自己的小洞里了
You're trapped in that little hole of yours.
就像一只无路可逃的猪 等着被我屠杀
Trapped like a pig I'm going to slaughter.
谁一点钟来看病
Who's my 1:00?
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
Uh, Michael Scofield.
我误会你了斯科菲尔德 这是你要的 方纳克
I was wrong about you, Scofield. Here's your PUGNAC.
稍微有点晚
Little bit late.
但总比没有强 对吧
Better late than never, right?
斯科菲尔德 去医务室
Scofield! Infirmary!
去看看就知道了
We'll see about that.
我迟早会知道的
I'm gonna find out, you know...
你去那里的真正目的
what it is you're doing up there.
需要多长时间
How long does this take?
过去会花上几个小时
It used to take hours.
他们最终发明了新的葡萄糖检测仪器
They've come a long way with the new glucose kits
现在只需10妙
This'll take us about ten seconds.
将剥片放进仪器 结果会马上出来
Slide the strip into the meter, we're ready to go.
我想你肯定知道
I'm sure you know this,
非糖尿病患者的 平均葡萄糖含量是每公升1000毫克
but average glucose for the non-diabetic is about 100 milligrams per deciliter,
如果结果在这个范围内 就说明误诊了
so we see a number like that here, and we know you've been misdiagnosed.
你看起来很紧张
You seem nervous.
有么
I do?
你在出汗
You're sweating.
一定是因为打针的缘故
Must be the needles.
一直不太习惯打针
Never really got used to them.
你患糖尿病还纹身 真不敢相信
Somehow, with diabetes and that tattoo, I find that hard to believe.
恐怕是坏消息
Bad news, I'm afraid.
每公升含1800毫克 你的确得了糖尿病
180 milligrams per deciliter. You're definitely diabetic.
还需要我做些什么不
Do you need anything else from me?
做好打针的准备
Arm to stick a needle in.
没问题
Okay.
星期三见
I'll see you Wednesday.
-有意思 -一个囚犯而已
-Cute. -Prisoner.
我也说不好 他看起来有点古怪
I don't know. There's something strange about him.
你说什么
What do you mean?
我告诉他验血结果
I gave him the results of his blood test,
他脸上却表现出
and there was this look on his face.
某种 嗯
It was, um...
解脱的表情
relief.
没事
It's all right
我带他走吧
I got it.
正好我正要去A区呢
I'm headed over to A-Wing anyhow.
您看起来气色不错 长官
You're positively beaming, boss.
人逢喜事精神爽
Got up on the right side of the bed this morning, I guess.
等一下
Hold up.
我去加点糖
Sugar.
别乱动 小嫩鸡
Don't you move, Fishy.
嘿 你们要干什么
Hey, what are you doing?
跟我们走 小嫩鸡
You're coming with us, Fish.
咱俩的游戏玩了有段时间了
This little polka you and I have been doing for a while
此时此刻
as of this moment...
该有个了断了
it's over.
菲波纳奇
Fibonacci.
我想知道你是怎么找到他的
I want to know how you got to him...
还有他现在在哪儿
and where he is, right now.
想都别想 约翰
Not going to happen, John.
现在我数三下
Now, I'm going to count to three.
如果我告诉了你 那我才死定了
give you that information, I'm a dead man.
这你我都知道
You know it and I know it.
出去之后我会告诉你的 在这之前决不可能
I'll tell you the moment we're outside those walls,not a second before.
你现在就得告诉我
You tell me now.
不可能的 约翰
Not gonna happen, John.
我再给你最后一次机会
I'm going to give you one last chance.